RG 004:150, Washington Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Washington Probate Court records
1832-1986, bulk 1832-1976
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Washington District)
43 cubic feet
Record books, 1832-1924; Bond record books, 1881-1965; Probate files, 1832-1986, bulk 1832-1976.
RG004_150
2011-044, 2012-026
Historical Note
Washington, Litchfield County, Town established in May 1779, Parent Towns: Kent, Litchfield, New Milford, and Woodbury
The Washington Probate District was constituted May 22, 1832, from the Litchfield and Woodbury Probate Districts. The Washington Probate District merged with the Oxford, Roxbury, Southbury, and Woodbury Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Region #22 Probate District which serves the municipalities of Bethlehem, Oxford, Roxbury, Southbury, Washington, Watertown, and Woodbury.
Town of Washington, Probate District chronology:
January 1779 - May 1832, Litchfield District
January 1779 - May 21, 1832, Woodbury District (covered Judea Society, i.e. the parts of town taken from New Milford and Woodbury)
May 22, 1832 - January 4, 2011, Washington District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Region # 22 District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, volumes 1-16, 1832-1965. Contact the probate court to access original record books after volume 16. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1832-1986, bulk 1832-1976. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies.
Arrangement
Record books in accession 2012-026 are numbered from 1-16.
Probate files in accession 2011-044 are arranged in two alphabetic sequences. The first sequence in boxes 1 through 12 contains files that are tri-folded and cover 1832-1951, bulk 1832-1943. The second sequence in boxes 13 through 35 contains file folders and covers 1893-1986, bulk 1920-1976.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the files in accession 2011-044.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Washington
Places:
Washington (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2012-026, Record books, 1832-1965, and Accession 2011-044, Probate files, 1832-1986, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Probate files from 1921-1946 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-3, 5, 7, 9-10, 13, 1832-1917, were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The record books in accession 2012-026 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on March 12, 2012.
The probate files in accession 2011-044 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on November 19, 2010 and January 20, 2011.
Container List
- Record books, 1832-1965, bulk 1832-1924; 8 cubic feet (16 volumes); 2012-026
  - Records, 1832-1846 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1846-1855 (Volume 2)
    On spine: "Manuscript"
  - Records, 1856-1882 (Volume 3)
  - Decrees, 1869-1888 (Volume 4)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Records, 1871-1883 (Volume 5)
  - Bonds, 1881-1910 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1883-1892 (Volume 7)
  - Decrees, 1888-1902 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1892-1897 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1898-1904 (Volume 10)
  - Decrees, 1902-1913 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1904-1910 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1910-1917 (Volume 13)
  - Bonds, 1911-1965 (Volume 14)
  - Decrees, 1913-1924 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1917-1924 (Volume 16)
- Probate files, 1832-1986, bulk 1832-1976; 35 cubic feet; 2011-044
  - Abbott - Black, R. (Box 1)
  - Black, T. - Calhoun, Henry (Box 2)
  - Calhoun, Herman - Crofut (Box 3)
  - Crother - Gear (Box 4)
  - Geer - Hickox, L. (Box 5)
  - Hickoc, M. - Kinney, D. (Box 6)
  - Kinney, E. - Mitchell, E. (Box 7)
  - Mitchell, H. - Pendleton (Box 8)
  - Perkins - Seeley, A. (Box 9)
  - Seeley, B. - Titus, L. (Box 10)
  - Titus, S. - Wilson (Box 11)
  - Winters - Zumph (Box 12)
  - Aal - Baldwin (Box 13)
  - Barley - Barnes, Hattie (Box 14)
  - Barnes, Hattie - Blixt (Box 15)
  - Boles - Brassert (Box 16)
  - Brick - Buxton (Box 17)
  - Cable - Conroy, M. (Box 18)
  - Conroy, W. - Dodd (Box 19)
  - Dougal - Findlay (Box 20)
  - Finn - Greene (Box 21)
  - Greenslag - Hinchliffe (Box 22)
  - Hinchman - Jagger, H. (Box 23)
  - Jagger, L. - Kennedy (Box 24)
  - Kenney - Lamson (Box 25)
  - Landi - McGrath (Box 26)
  - McGugan - Neergaard (Box 27)
  - Nelson - Placek, A. (Box 28)
  - Placek, L. - Rushmore, David (Box 29)
  - Rushmore, David, trust accounting (Box 30)
  - Russell - Signor (Box 31)
  - Sjonost - Taylor, Ellen (Box 32)
  - Taylor, Eugene - Voss (Box 33)
  - Wachcic - Wightman (Box 34)
  - Wilbur - Zumph (Box 35)